Curriculum Vitae - Pete Moore

Introduction

I have more than two decades' experience in the data industry, and I love helping organisations get the most from their data. I advise on data strategy. I code at expert level in R, Python and SQL. I have hands-on experience with the following machine learning and deep learning algorithms and methodologies: collaborative filtering, association rules, k-means, restricted Boltzmann machines, convolutional neural networks. I have composed code using the following deep learning platforms: Tensorflow, Keras, DL4J. This list however is not exhaustive because I strongly believe that the problem picks the platform and I am always willing to enhance my skill set accordingly. I'm constantly learning and refining my skills and am currently studying for an MSc Data Science at the University of Dundee (expected: Distinction). My ethos is that it always starts with the data.

Skills profile

- SQL: SQL Server Versions: 2017, 2016, 2012, 2000; Platforms: Windows, Linux (in Docker)
- R: R3.0-3.5+; RStudio 0.99-1.1+; on Windows/Mac
- Python: Python 3.5-3.7+; typically with Anaconda (preferred IDE is Spyder)
- Data warehousing: SSRS, SSAS, SSIS, DTS (all versions)
- Data visualisation: Power BI¹, Tableau, Rmarkdown, R (ggplot, Shiny), Python (matplotlib)
- Machine learning algorithms: collaborative filtering, association rules, k-means, restricted Boltzmann machines, convolutional neural networks
- Deep learning platforms: Tensorflow, Keras, DL4J

Experience

Founder, Look at your Data Ltd - Jan 2017 - Dec 2018

Look at your Data delivered GDPR training to medium-sized groups of varied backgrounds, organisations and technical abilities.

Non-executive Director, ManchesterSQL - Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

I was an inaugural member of ManchesterSQL, a not-for-profit that organised the annual SQL Saturday conference and the monthly SQL Server User Group.

IT Director, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Sep 2004 - Dec 2016

I was responsible for the data and IT at Evolution, a global recruitment company.

As IT Director I was responsible for: search algorithms across a corpus of over five million CV's; natural language processing (NLP), for example, to parse job descriptions from CVs; BI provision from consultant to board meeting; strategic IT direction of the company from infrastructure virtualisation to architecture of

¹for the Power BI Data Viz of this CV see: http://bit.ly/PeteMooreDataViz

data estate. Responsible for internationalisation of sales practices and localisation of database. The voice of IT on the board. Often a counterpoint to sales wisdom.

IT Director, Evolution Recruitment Solutions – Jan 2012 - Dec 2016

I joined the board of Evolution in 2012 and the full board one year later. The first person ever to break into the inner circle having been a junior in the company.

- Virtualised Infrastructure: the organisation's international expansion entailed my supervision of an expansion in infrastructure. Using VMWare we virtualised the entire server estates and incorporated VDI's for peripatetic desktop users. Thus providing IaaS.
- Data warehouse
- Built a highly effective and collaborative team of twelve people who became Microsoft Gold Partners, an industry first
- Successfully introduced Kanban working practices across the organisation.
- MI as a habit: as a result of cross-enterprise management and careful stakeholder management, the
 business respected KPI's. The data warehouse behind these informed very important business decision.
 That is, data-driven operation as habit. This entailed the delivery of high level metrics such as profit to
 low level measures like call minutes.

IT Manager, Evolution Recruitment Solutions – Jan 2007 - Dec 2011

After two years at Evolution my job title changed from Data- to IT- Manager. My main passion remained data, but the still small business need a comprehensive function and I was the obvious candidate to lead it.

This period began with the great recession, the opportunity create by this led to rapid UK-based expansion and culminated in a small single-brand, single-office, single-country, single-language company being turned into a multi-national, multiple brand enterprise.

- Migration from SQL Server 2000 to SQL Server 2008.
- MI as standard.
- Build and A/B testing of commercial websites.
- Establishment of scalable helpdesk function with replicable job units.
- Establishment of Data Management function.
- Pioneering of Database as a Service model (on SQL Server 2008) to allow a franchise-based business model.

Data Manager, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Sep 2004 - Dec 2006

My initial role at Evolution started when I was younger and more audacious. "If you can say it, I can code it" were the exact words that left my mouth. Whilst I never quite regretted them, it led to some interesting projects. Simply, no idea was too big and the projects we worked on then would one day be called "Data Science".

- Complex algorithms for CV matching and importing in SQL Server VB.Net and VB6.
- Wages automation in SQL Server and classic ASP.
- Elementary machine learning for email analysis.
- Establishment of Data Team plus basic support infrastructure.
- Introduction of per-consultant MI using SQL Server and ASP.

2018-09-07

Senior Data Manager, LBM - Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

LBM used data to drive direct marketing campaigns in the B2B sector.

Senior Data Manager, LBM - Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

LBM demanded and if you didn't deliver you were out. I was in charge of the most important database in the company. Achieving this meant taking SQL Server and knowing the product inside out; going from apprentice to subject matter expert. If this seems unreasonable: it was. I didn't enjoy working at LBM, but I did learn a lot.

Data Specialist, Inter • Act Systems - Aug 1999 - Apr 2002

Inter • Act leveraged EPOS data to provide B2C offers through kiosk technology.

Business Applications Specialist, Inter • Act Systems - Apr 2001 - Apr 2002

Introduction to OLAP, ROLAP, Set-based programming using Business Objects Software.

Data Analyst, Inter • Act Systems – Aug 1999 - Apr 2000

Providing, interpreting and automating reports for sales teams.

Hobbies

In a lifetime of travel, I have scaled many of Europe's highest peaks, hiked fifty miles in a day for charity, and I have visited every US state apart from Hawaii. I even wrote a (bad) book about the latter.

I follow football, cricket, baseball and NFL. Sometimes to a level bordering on excessive. Ditto rock music, popular science and computing. I am genuinely passionate about my muse and don't differentiate studying about data from reading for pleasure.

In my spare time I like to perform stand-up and improv.

Public speaking

As one who spends their spare time performing improv and stand-up comedy, it stands to reason that I like public speaking.

As a data professional I am fortunate enough to get invited to speak in locations as far afield as Ljubljana, Copenhagen but mostly Manchester. I have spoken in public on the facets of data that mean most to me: how to code well, how to communicate data by visualisation, to your boss and, fundamentally, how to keep this ethical.

Volunteering

Table 1: Volunteering details

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
Leader	Microsoft (PASS Chapter)	Lancashire	Jan-2017	Dec-2017

2018-09-07 3

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
Organiser	ManchesterSQL	Lancashire	Jan-2017	Dec-2017
Owner	FC United	Lancashire	May-2005	Dec-2021

Summer work

Table 2: Summer work details

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
Rides Assistant	Santa Cruz Beach Boardwalk	California	Jun-1998	Sep-1998
Games Assistant	Family Kingdom Amusement Park	South Carolina	Jun-1997	Sep-1997
Data Analyst	John Dickinson Stationery	Hertfordshire	Jun-1996	Sep-1996
Assistant Project Manager	Nat West	London	Jun-1995	Sep-1995

Education

Table 3: Education details

Position	Institution	Place	From	То
MSc Data Science	University of Dundee	Angus	Jan-2017	Jan-2019
MSci Mathematical Physics (2:1)	University of Nottingham	Nottinghamshire	Oct-1995	Jun-1999
A-levels (AAAB)	Longdean School	Hertfordshire	Sep-1993	Jun-1995

Community profile

- GitHub²: https://github.com/databackwriter
- Blog: https://databackwriter.com
- Twitter: https://twitter.com/thedatabloke
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lookatmydata/
- $\bullet \ \, StackOverflow: \ https://stackexchange.com/users/12936623/pete-moore$

CV edition information (internal use only)

Data Scientist CV issue 1003(1003) for Peter Moore

2018-09-07 4

 $^{^2}$ for the R markdown that created this CV see: https://github.com/databackwriter/Pete-Moore---Data-Scientist---CV